Guide to the Isaac Rabinowitz papers, [ca. 1965-1988]
Rabinowitz, Issac papers
- Series III. Research, Papers, Articles and Books Arranged by Subject
  - 'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew
    - 'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      Includes notes, manuscripts, and copies
    - 'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form in Preterite Contexts: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew (Box 7, Folder 40)
      Copy
    - 'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form in Preterite Contexts: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew (Box 7, Folder 41)
      Copy and a short note
  - Other Notes (in Alphabetical Order)
    - Aramaic-Lydian Bilingual (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Bibliography, R in 19th Century. etc. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Bibliography--Rhetorica (Box 7, Folder 43-1)
    - Cassuto, Colorni, Rorenbeeg, et, al (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 3, 4 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Summary of Deuteronomy
    - Concise Aramaic Grammar-Bauer-Leander (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Concise Biblical Aramaic Grammar (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Contains manuscript "Shorter Biblical Aramaic Grammar by Hans Bauer and Pontus Leander, Translated and Adapted from German into English by Isaac Rabinowitz" and "Course in Biblical, Palestinian Jewish and Babylonian Talmudic Aramaic"
    - Cratylus (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Damascus" Fragments IX:1-Revue de Qumran (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Daskyleion (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Also contains some offprints.
    - de Vaux Fragment, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Correspondence on Isaac Rabinowitz's article in "de Vaux Fragment of an Unknown Work"
    - Entsi klopediah mi krait (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Mainly notes, also contains offprints
    - Entsi klopediah mi krait (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Notes, correspondence
    - Ezekiel (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - First Copy: Ancient Israel's Theory of Literature (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Fourth Century B.C.E. Aramaic Papyrus from Samaria (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Genesis 2:18-20; Theme of Gen.-IK:10, Implications of the Scriptures as World-Plan for the Compilation of the Scripture Production (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Cornell Alumni News, 1957-1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Issues containing Isaac Rabinowitz's articles.
    - Gen 21:7 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Sarah's wish
    - Gen 22:13 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Genesis Apocryphon (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Hebrew in American College and University Sites" by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Hebrew papyri: Photostats, etc. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Hold-Various notes on Scrolls and Other Studies (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Isaiah, I and II (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Jeremiah (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Jonah (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Kipurim, etc. (Box 8, Folder 25)
      Contains notes, correspondence, and copies
    - Language Notecards (Hebrew, Latin, Greek) (Box 7)
    - "Literature as Perceived by the Creators of the Hebrew Bible" by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Maimonides: Notecards (Box 8)
    - Material for Summary Chapter (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Material on Biblical Rhetoric (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Obadiah (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Oneirokritikon (Box 8, Folder 30)
      Notes and offprint
    - Preface to Biblical Hebrew Literature, "Memoranda", paper (Box 8, Folder 31)
      Also contains syllabus for Lit 360
    - Psalms//Parallelism (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Psalms-Scroll Notes; 11QPsxa (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Q Psa-David's Compositions (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Quotation in Bible: Interpreter's Dictionary, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      Contains correspondence about dictionary purchase and Professor Rabinowitz's copy of the pages he contributed to the dictionary
    - Samuel II Translations: chapter 15, 16, 17 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Sefer ha-yashar (Joshua 10:12-14-II Samuel 1:18) (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Sarbalchthanel (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Sarbēth Sarbane EL (Box 8, Folder 39)
      notes and offprint
    - Scriptural Interpretation: its notes in relation to normative fund, etc (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Scroll-Papers (Box 8, Folder 41)
      About the "Damascus" Fragments. Also contains several offprints.
    - Shir ha-shirim (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Syriac ms. Notes (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Text, Conat, etc. (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - "The Crux at Amos 3:12" by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - "The Hebrew Bible as a Literary Unity" by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 8, Folder 46)
      Also contains syllabus for Semitics 330/Comparative Literature 323
    - War-Scroll-1QM (Box 8, Folder 47)
      Translation of War Scroll
    - Yem. Nebuch. Apocryphon (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Other Articles (in Alphabetical Order)
    - Ahisefer, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      A journal that contains Isaac Rabinowitz's Essay
    - Ephphathá, etc (Box 8, Folder 50)
      Contains correspondence, offprints, copies, and notes
    - Ephphathá, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - JWB Circle in Jewish Bookland, 1953-1957 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      Contains Isaac Rabinowitz's article "A Book That Abounds in High-Soaring Hypotheses"
    - Kiev Festschrift, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 53)
      Contains copies of "A Rectification of the Date of Judah Messer Leon's Death" by Prof. Rabinowitz, written for Dr. I. Edward Kiev's Festschrift
    - Moreh Tsede k (Box 8, Folder 54)
      Contains "The Guide of Righteousness" by Professor Rabinowitz and notes
    - Papers relating to the "Power of the Word" debate: Professor Rabinowitz's papers and those of Ban, Theslton and others (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Samaritan-Arabic Ms, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Speeches, Sermons, Articles, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - The Brooklyn Jewish Center Review, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 58)
      Contains Isaac Rabinowitz's Article "The Greatest Manuscript Find of Our Time"
    - "The Qumran Authors' SPR HHGW|Y" (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Contains copies, notes, and correspondence
    - Writings, Speeches, etc. (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Contains "What shall we offer our youth?" and "Jewish Attitudes of Jewish College Youth" section 2, both by Isaac Rabinowitz
- Series IV. Offprints of Articles, Writings by Isaac Rabinowitz
  - "Another Aramaic Record of the North-Arabian Goddess Han-Ilat", 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Entsi klopediah mi krait (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Sarah's Wish (Gen. XXI 6-7) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "The Alleged Orphism of 11Q PSS 28 3-12", 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "The Meaning and Date of 'Damascus Document IX, 1", 1968 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "The Qumran Authors' SPR HHGW|Y", 1961 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "The Meaning of the Key ('Demetrius')-Passage of the Qumran Nahum-Pesher", 1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Isaac Rabinowitz's Offprints 1 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Isaac Rabinowitz's Offprints 2 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Isaac Rabinowitz's Offprints 3 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Series V. Courses, Offered Mainly by Isaac Rabinowitz
  - Ancient Israel's Theory of Literature-Seminar, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Arabs and Arabica, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Aramaic 451 Notes, etc., 1954-1969 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Aramaic Courses, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Comparative Literature 301, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Comparative Literature 301: Topics for Papers, 1966-1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Comparative Literature 302 Dead Sea Scrolls in Their Literary and Historical Context, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Comparative Literature 323/Semitics 330, Fall Term 1973, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Comparative Literature 324/Semitics 331, Literature of Nascent Judaism and Christianity, Syllabus,etc., 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Dead Sea Scroll-Seminar-Qumranica (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Exams in Hebrew and Aramaic, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Graded Examinations--Confidential (Box 9, Folder 23-1)
  - Hebrew 102 (Notes on Ruth) (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Hebrew 201: Bereshit, March, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Hebrew 201: I Samuel (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Hebrew 201-2: Notes: Mainly Shofetim and yeshayahu (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Hebrew 202 (Notes on Readings) Parallelism, 1960-1964 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Hebrew 202-Amos/Psalms (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Hebrew 204, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Literature 206-Lectures (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Literature 301-Quotations and Topics for Student Essays, 1967-1977 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Literature 302/Semitic 331/Comparative Literature 324, Topics for Student Papers, etc. (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Literature 206/302-Syllabus, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Literature of Ancient Israel, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    Also contains offprints of papers by Professor Rabinowitz
  - Pre-Christian Jewish Literature, Spring 1973 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Sanhedrin: Class Notes (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Semitics-Syllabi-Exams, 1967-1977 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Semitics 102-103: Elementary Classical Hebrew-Exams, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Semitics 330/Comparative Literature 323-Fall Terms; Near Eastern Studies 331, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Semitics 453: Syriac, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Semitics 453-454: Syriac (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Wayne State University Courses, Department of Semitics, etc., 1956-1960 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Wayne State Hebrew Courses (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Wayne State Jewish History Courses, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Wayne State Jewish Thought Courses, 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Series VI. Speeches and Lectures
  - "A Recovered Key to the Understanding of the Hebrew Bible", 1972 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    Speech notes, correspondence, and newspaper clippings
  - "A Recovered Key to the Understanding of the Hebrew Bible" (Box 9, Folder 48)
    Speech notes
  - "A Recovered Key to the Understanding of the Hebrew Scriptures," Galveston Talk, Feb 18, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Materials on Newark and Detroit Scroll-Lectures 1955-56: Publicity, Newspaper articles on Dead Sea Scrolls, notes, etc., 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Messenger Lectures, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    "From The Hasmoneans to Bar-Kochba" by Dr. Yigael Yadin; schedule and correspondence
  - Pencilled Drafts of Lectures (Box 9, Folder 52)
    "The Hebrew Bible as a literary Unity", "The Nature and Function of Sepher Hayyashar"
  - Personal Business; Lecture Invitations, etc., 1956 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Qumran Scroll-Lectures, etc.-Sanders Bibliography (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Radio Interview with Joe Leeming, November 22, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Record of Extra, 1959-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Correspondence about delivering speeches
  - Research Club Lecture: Qumran Scrolls, Dead Sea Scrolls, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Michigan Hillel Foundation: Speeches and Writings, 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: Ithaca, 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Talk to Bill Kaven's Class, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Wesleyan Lectures, April 17-28, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series VII. Scholarly or Critical Reviews by Isaac Rabinowitz
  - Book Reviews by Isaac Rabinowitz, Dupont-Sommer, A. and Zeitlin, Solomon, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - In Jewish Bookland, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Contains correspondence with Jewish Book Council of America and a copy of Jewish Bookland
  - Review for JAOS (Journal of the American Oriental Society) [of Smolar/Aberbach/Churgin: TJ to the Prophets] and Fishbane, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    "Targum Jonathan to the Prophet" by Pinkhos Churgin, "Studies in Targum Jonathan to the Prophet" by Leivy Smolar and Moses Aberbach
  - Fishbane Review-JAOS, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Isaac Rabinowitz's review of "Biblical Interpretation in Ancient Israel" by Michael Fishbane
  - Review of Jean. Le Moyne, Les Sadducéens-J.Carignac, Editor, R. de Qumran, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Journal of Semitic Studies-James Barr-etc., 1964-1973 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "The Error-Born Orphism of 11Q PSS 28:3-12", 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    The article is written by Isaac Rabinowitz. The file also contains some offprints and correspondence.
  - "Trever's Taw and Orlinsky's Argument" by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - William Brownlee (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Contains Isaac Rabinowitz's review for William Brownlee and some offprints, journals
  - JBL Reviews, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    (Journal of Biblical Literature.) The file also contains Review by J.Hoftijzer
- Series VIII. Collection of Journals and Others' Work
  - Amos Funkenstein, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Andrew and Nancy Ramage, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Aramaic Offprints (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Averroes: Talkhis on Aristotle's Rhetoric: Ms. Florence (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Dead Sea Scroll, etc. Offprints, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    By Yigael Yadin
  - "Greek Inscriptions"-Typescript (author unidentified) (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Inscription of Eliba'al (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - J.A. Emerton, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Offprints
  - Joseph. E. Fontenrose, 1960-1974 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Lasinio: Averroes' Talkhis on Aristotle's Rhetoric, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Leiden Ms. Averroes/Rhetoric (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Mid-East Intelligence Survey, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Moshe Pelli-Offprints (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Offprints, 1960-1972 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Offprints: Bible and Dead Sea Scrolls, 1957-1973 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Offprints-1988 by Gary A. Rendsburg, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Rouleau du Temple de Qoumrân / A. Caquot (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Some Pages of the Paris Ms. of the Arabic Version of Aristotle's Rhetoric (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Staff Papers, etc. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Interpreter's Dictionary of the Bible (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "The Naming of Isaac" by John Ronning, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Toaff off-Prints on Italian Jewry, 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Toaff off-Prints on Italian Jewry, 2 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Todros (1st Paris Ms.) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Todros (2nd Paris Ms.) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - W.G. Rabinowitz: "Rôle of Eleaticism in Aristotle's Discussion of Moral Virtue", 1960 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Journals and Newspaper, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Series IX. Reactions, Criticisms, and Reports
  - Cornell Reporter/Cornell Chronicle Stories and Inquiries, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Lit. -Reaction and Criticisms (including Norwell Therien and Bernhard Kendler), 1973-1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Reactions to Nopheth Suphim (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Towards A Valid Theory of Biblical Literature, 1964-1969 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Series X. Book Collections and Purchases
  - Books, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Purchase Receipts
  - Book Collection Expenses, 1949-1970 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Receipts and correspondence
  - Book Purchases, etc. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Book Purchases and Correspondence-"In Jewish Bookland", etc., 1955-1957 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Otto Harrassowitz-Wiesbaden, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Receipts and Correspondence
  - Rare Hebraica-Judaica Collection, 1972-1988 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Rare Judaica Collection, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Rare Judaica Collection, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Report about Rabinowitz Collection, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Sale of Zimara 1516 ed. Vol. 1 of Aristotle-Averroes to Wellcome Library, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Series XI. Travels
  - Travel/Banking, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Travel Expenses, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Trip to Europe and Israel, June 9, 1962-September 9,1962 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Kansas City Trip, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Trip to Israel, Mar 20-May 4, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Trip to N.Y.-Philadelphia, December, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Trip - Nopheth Suphim. Letter, etc., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Series XII. Bound Manuscripts from Rabinowitz collection #4661
  - [Ḳovets be-khishuf], 18--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 1; 103 leaves; 15 cm.
    Author: Unknown
    Notes: Ms., written in a Greek-Sephardi hand. This ms. is a fortune-teller's handbook. Many graffiti, some in Greek and Judaeo-Greek. Sefer ha-goralot is attributed to Abraham ibn Ezra.
    Table of contents: Urim ṿe-tumim (leaves 6a-31a)
    Sefer ha-goralot / Even ʻEzra (leaves 33b-44a)
    Shaʻar toldot bene Adam (leaf 46b)
    Reʻamim u-raʻashim (leaf 47b)
    Segulot u-ḳemeʻot (leaves 49a-52b)
    Goralot / Saʻadyah Ga'on (leaves 55b-68a)
  - Totseʼot ḥayim, Reshit ḥokhmah. Selections, 16--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 2 tiny; [93] p.; 15 cm.
    Author: Vidas, Elijah ben Moses de
    Notes: Ms., written in a North African Sephardi hand. Totseʼot ḥayim is an abridgement of Vidas' ethical and cabalistic work Reshit ḥokhmah. It is probably a transcription of the Amsterdam printed ed. of 1650. Title from running title. Also includes his Yoreh ḥaṭaʼim ba-derekh (drawn from Isaiah Horowitz' Shene luḥot ha-Berit).
  - [Kelale Shemuʼel], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 3; [166] p.; 20 cm.
    Author: Sid, Samuel Ibn
    Notes: Ms., written in an East European Ashkenazi hand. Includes: Kelale Shemuʼel (Samuel's Rules); with additional notes by an unknown Talmudist in a second scribal hand.
  - [Legal works], 18--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 4-5; [96] leaves (in 2 cases); 23 cm.
    Author: Albuḥair, David
    Notes: Ms., in a Sephardi hand. Author's autograph on several leaves. Ms. contains novellae (on Talmud), liḳuṭim (on Maimonides), responsa (correspondence with various contemporary legal authorities). In cases labeled: Legal works.
  - [Papers of Rabbi Ishmael Cohen of Modena], 1738-1799; 4661 Bd. Ms. 6++; [67] leaves; 38 cm.
    Author: Ishmael ben Abraham Isaac ha-Kohen
    Notes: Ms., of variantly sized sheets. Written in an Italian hand except for a long letter (5 long sheets) of Responsa (written in Ashkenazi cursive script), from an East European authority, perhaps R. Reuben Selig Ashkenazi of Zamoscz. Papers include: Novellae on Talmud and Maimonides' Code, Responsa, Confession-formulary for the eve of Rosh ha-Shanah, homiletical notes on Genesis.
  - Sefer Shemen ha-mishḥah, Shemen ha-mishḥah, 18--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 7; 34 leaves: ill.; 24 cm.
    Author: Shemuʾel ben Mosheh Ḥayim.
    Notes: Ms., written in a Sephardi hand. Text is mainly on civil law, legal responsa. Inscribed leaves are in various sizes. With vignette. Part 1, only, of this work was printed in Constantinople in 1840. In case labeled: Samuel b. Moses Hayyim.
  - [Kitve ha-Ari annotations], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 8; [192] leaves, bound: 1 ill.; 21 cm.
    Author: Vital, Ḥayyim ben Joseph
    Notes: Ms., written in an East European cursive hand. Annotations, mainly by Vital on various aspects of the Lurianic Kabalah. An owner of the ms., writing in 1879, has added marginal notes indicating other works in which portions of the material are to be found (leaves [1-159]). An additional work is included (leaves [161-192]) consisting of annotations of Vital's Otsrot hayim, attributed to R. Natan Spira and to Mosheh Zakuto. This work is written in an East European Rashi-script. Title on spine: Kithebhe ha-ʼAri. Notes by I. Rabinowitz inserted.
  - [Otsrot Ḥayim], Lurianic Kabbalah, 16--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 9-10+; 167 leaves (bound in 2 v.); 26 cm.
    Author: Vital, Hayyim ben Joseph
    Notes: Ms., written in a North African hand. Annotations by Avraham Azulai and others. This ms. is quite different from the printed eds. of this work. Leaves are missing at the beginning and end of the ms. In cases labeled: Lurianic Kabbalah.
  - [Derushim ʻal sefer Otsrot Ḥayim], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 11; [180] p.: ill.; 22 cm.
    Notes: Ms., written in East European Ashkenazi cursive hand. Nine disquisitions based upon Sefer Otsrot Ḥayim.
  - Afṭariot ha-Torah, Haftarot. Aramaic & Hebrew, 1673; 4661 Bd. Ms. 12; [178] leaves; 22 cm. (4to)
    Notes: Ms., originated in Yemen. Title taken from caption. Scripture and Targum in superlinear vocalization.
  - [Seder ṿe-Tashlikh; [ṿe], Seder Hoshaʻna Raba], Seder Tashlikh, 18--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 13; [80] p.; 18 cm.
    Notes: Ms., written in several Italian hands. Liturgy from Minhag Carpentras.
  - [Sidur, Temani], Siddur (Yemen), 1511-1650; 4661 Bd. Ms. 14-16++; [184], [6] leaves (in 3 cases); 33 cm.
    Notes: Ms., in Yemenite script. In addition to daily, Sabbath, and festival prayers, the ms. contains Pirḳe Avot, Scroll of the Hasmoneans (in Aramaic), blessing-formulae, a calendrical work and calendrical tables, a legal document formulary, poems and hymns (by Ibn Gabirol, Yehudah Halevi, A. Ibn Ezra, etc.). The ms. is dated 1511 for some parts; 1649-1650 for others.
  - [Sidur minhag Sefarad], 1792; 4661 Bd. Ms. 17-18; 145 leaves (bound in 2 v.); 17 cm.
    Notes: Ms., North African Sephardi. The Siddur has many additions and Kaṿanot of mystical character; also calendrical texts. In cases labeled: Siddur, minhag Sepharad.
  - Maḥazor, 1832; 4661 Bd. Ms. 19; [212] leaves; 23 cm.
    Notes: Ms., in Yemenite script. Title taken from caption title. Includes prayers for Festivals and the Fast of the 9th day of Av. Other texts include: Scroll of the Hasmoneans (in Hebrew, Aramaic and Arabic [treated as if sacred Scripture]; Pirḳe Avot; Midrash of the Ten Commandments, Peṭirat Aharon and Peṭirat Mosheh (in Judaeo-Arabic); legal and ritual formularies; calendrical pieces (mainly in Judaeo-Arabic), etc.
  - Sefer shel pizmonin di moʻadim zeh sefer shel ʻAzaryah Laṭaś me-ʻir Ḳuni, 1799; 4661 Bd. Ms. 20; 56 leaves: ill.; 24 cm.
    Notes: Ms., compiled by Azariah Lattes of Cuneo (Italy) in accord with the liturgy of Provence. Title taken from leaf [14a]. Original t.p. has an erasure: Zeh sefer pizmonim shel moʻadim di ---]. At head of title of original t.p.: Sefer.
  - [Maḥazor le-Rosh ha-Shanah, minhag Ḳarpenṭrats], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 21; 130 leaves; 20 cm.
    Author: Maḥzor (Carpentras, France). Rosh ha-Shanah
    Notes: Title on case: Minhag carpentras. Ms., written in Provençal script.
  - [Maḥazor Sukot, Shemini ʻatseret ṿe-Śimḥat Torah lefi minhag Ḳarpenṭrats], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 22; [333] p.; 19 cm.
    Author: Maḥzor (Carpentras, France). Sukkot
    Notes: Ms., written in a Provençal hand. Includes: Liturgy for Sukot, Hoshaʻna raba, Shemini ʻatseret,and Śimḥat Torah in the minhag of Carpentras, France.
  - [Sheḥiṭah], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 23; [148] p.; 21 cm.
    Notes: Ms., written in a Sephardi hand. Includes: 1. Various texts on matters germane to ritual meat-slaughtering (including some poetry); 2. ha-Ḥibur meha-Bediḳot / Nisim ha-Kohen; 3. Responsa on the laws of sheḥiṭah, based on the Code of Maimonides. Includes some Judaeo-Italian and Italian graffiti.
  - Sefer toldot Yitsḥaḳ, 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 24; 226 leaves: ill.; 19 cm.
    Author: Isaac ben David Alzera
    Notes: Ms., written in a North-African Sephardi hand. Text is a miscellany, containing calendrical and meteorological texts, a work on grammar, various homilies, and other material, not all the original work of this compiler. With vignette.
  - Liḳutim ʻal ha-Torah me-S. Naḥal Ḳedumim, Naḥal Ḳedumim. Selections, 18--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 25+; [29] p. (2 columns); 23 cm.
    Author: Azulai, Hayyim Joseph David
    Notes: In case labeled: Sepher Nahal Qedumim. Ms., Yemenite, is an abridgement of the printed text, probably printed in Livorno, Italy, in 1794. The last 7 p. are copied by a second ms. hand., with notes and comments of mainly mystical character.
  - [Perush ʻal Perush ha-Torah le-Rashi], 18--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 26 tiny; 46 leaves; 17 cm.
    Notes: Ms., North African, Sephardi. Commentary on Genesis 6:1-41:1. Unidentified author. A note on leaf [1] reads: "Zeh ha-sefer yotsro ṿe-gam ḥoḳro ha-Rav Maharam"Ṭ [mi-Ṭoledano?]. Several members of the Toledano family had written commentaries on Rashi's works.
  - [Midrash ha-Neʻelam; Shir ha-shirim; Rut; Ḳohelet; Maʻaśeh be-Ḥiram melekh Tsor], Bible. Five Scrolls. Selections., 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 27; [264] p.; 23 cm.
    Notes: Ms., originated in Yemen. Includes: Scripture and Targum of Song of Songs, with Targum in superlinear vocalization; Book of Ruth and Ecclesiastes with Targum and commentaries; portions of Midrash ha-Neʻelam; and, Maʻaśeh be-Ḥiram melekh Tsor.